## **CA ANUJ**

**3** 99904 56186

H.No-161, Gali No 5A, Near Telephone Exchange Samalka New Delhi-110037

### Summary

A Qualified Chartered Accountant having a sound experience of direct tax, indirect tax and audit of various organizations including construction, retailing, service, and education industry.

I intend to be a treasured resource for the organization I work with & join hands in hands to accomplish organizational aswell as personal goal.

I believe, even sky is not the limit, since there is always a scope of improvement; therefore, I want to contribute as much as Ican to my overall development.

4 years and above of experience in accounts, finance and taxation.

## **Experience**

**Assistant Manager** 

**CA Cooperative Thrift & Credit Society Limited** 

October 2021 to till date

Assistant Manager

Agarwal Ramesh K & Co.- Gurgaon

November 2019 to September 2021

Accountant

**Meatech Solutions LLP and Group Companies.** 

May 2017 to October 2019

Organization Description: Meatech Solutions LLP is an authorize distributor and service provider in the field of Surveying Instrument and Meteorological Instruments like Weather Station, Mining and Mobile Scanner etc.

**Article Assistant** 

Agarwal Ramesh K & Co.- Gurgaon

**April 2013 to April 2016** 

# **Statutory Audit**

- 1. Review & Testing of internal financial control.
- 2. Review of Companies Act compliance, Auditing standards & other statutory compliances.
- 3. Verification of Assets and Liabilities, Loan and advances, investment, debtors, creditor, contingent liabilities, deferred tax assets and liabilities, sale& purchase voucher etc.
- 4. Auditing the client financial statement by understanding the client's business & risk developing audit approach & preparation audit program and checklists for conducting the audit.
- 5. Preparing audit report including compliance of CARO, Note to accounts & making recommendations
- 6. Statutory audit and Concurrent audit of bank branches( Canara Bank, Union bank of India and State bank of bank)

### **Accounting and Other Works**

- 1. Preparation of Financial Statement as per schedule III of Companies Act 2013.
- 2. Preparation of Book of Accounts on accrual/cash Basis of various entities.
- 3. Analysis of Financial statement for various purposes like bank loan, due diligence and preparation of CMA Statement.
- 4. Preparation and Reconciliation of cash flow statement.
- 5. Finalization of Financial Statements.
- 6. Scrutiny of Sundry Debtor & Analysis of collection period.
- 7. Review of cash & Bank management including BRS.
- 8. Review of Contractor & Consultant Agreement.
- 9. Compilation & Maintenance of Accounting records of various entities.

- 10. Preparation of reports for project, MIS reconciliations, co-ordination with other groups within the organization, ability in process work like review of monthly and yearly account,
- 11. Preparation of documents for Import Export, Bank Guarantee, Letter of Credit.
- 12. Preparation and Filing ROC reporting for LLP and Private and Limited Company on Time like DIR-3KYC, INC-22A, AOC-4, MGT-7, DIR-12, DPT-3.LLP-11, LLP-8 and other Incorporation form.
- 13. Processing of Salary with all applicable compliance on salary likes TDS, EPF and ESI.

#### **Indirect Tax**

- 1. Preparation and filing of GSTR 9 & of 9C.
- 2. Preparation of reconciliation statement of GSTR 3B with Books of Accounts.
- 3. Preparation and filing of monthly GST returns.
- 4. Preparation and submission replies to various GST Notices, representation before assessing officers.

#### **Direct Tax**

- 1. Preparation and filing of Income tax return of various entities like Companies, RWA, Partnership, Individual and HUF
- 2. Preparation and Filing tax audit of individual, partnership firm, private limited and limited companies.
- 3. Preparation and submission replies to various income tax notices, representation before assessing officers at the time of case filling like Income Tax Department, and other assessments like Service Tax.
- 4. Preparation and filing of TDS/TCS Return like 24Q, 26Q, 27Q, 27EQ.
- 5. Preparation and filing of 15CA& 15CB for foreign remittances.

#### **Education**

Course/Examination	Institution/university/Board	Year Of Passing	Performance
CA Final – Group II	ICAI	May 2019	50.00%
CA Final – Group I	ICAI	May 2018	51.75%
B.Com(Hons)	Delhi University	2014	46.94%
CA IPCC- Group II	ICAI	November 2015	50.00%
CA IPPC- Group I	ICAI	November 2012	52.25%
СРТ	ICAI	June 2011	50.00%
12 <sup>th</sup> Class	CBSE	2011	62.5%
10 <sup>th</sup> Class	CBSE	2009	71.00%

## **Skills**

- Advanced Excel Skills including PivotTables and VLOOKUP Function.
- 35 Hours Orientation Program by ICAI
- Completed Advanced (ICITSS) MCS Course
- Tally ERP 9.0, Quick Book, Compu Tax Package for taxation
- Completed AICITSS Advance Information Technology.

#### **Personal Information**

Date of Birth : 19<sup>th</sup> June 1993 Father Name : Lokeshwar Language : English, Hindi Marital Status : Married

Hobbies : Traveling, Cricket

I hereby declare that the details furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.